# JP DILLINGHAM

# **Software/Systems Engineer**

E: jpdillingham@gmail.com | Р: (309) 749-8075 | w: http://dillingham.ws | LinkedIn: jpdillingham | GitHub: jpdillingham

# **Summary**

Senior level software engineer/systems engineer with 10 years of experience executing and managing projects in the Industrial Automation MES/MOM space with budgets up to \$5m and with involvement from first customer contact to completion. Experience managing and mentoring both direct reports and members of project teams across software, systems, mechanical and electrical engineering disciplines.

## **Experience**

## **Open Source Software Developer**

December 2015 - Present

Actively participating in Open Source Software development during off-work hours with repositories written in C# and Java. Member of the Free Software Foundation and the Open Source Initiative.

# **Senior Systems Engineer**

Grantek Systems Integration | December 2015 - Present

Functioning as a senior level engineer responsible for mid to large scale MES/MOM project specification, architecture, technical planning, and execution. Contributing individually with respect to new technologies, research and development, and the definition and implementation of standards and practices for the organization. Responsible for the technical engineering oversight and mentoring of junior and intermediate level engineers.

# **Manufacturing IT Manager**

Grantek Systems Integration | March 2014 – December 2015 (1 year 10 months)

Responsible for general management of the Manufacturing IT department of the Grantek Chicago office, including the management, scheduling, and career growth of four direct reports.

Responsible for the quotation, engineering oversight, and management of Industrial Automation MES/MOM projects with budgets in excess of \$5m and with teams as large as eight, spanning multiple disciplines and involving multiple customer sites and subcontractors. Functioned as Lead Developer and Technical Lead on the majority of managed projects.

## **Systems Engineer**

Grantek Systems Integration | August 2007 – March 2014 (6 years 8 months)

Responsible for the design, implementation, commissioning, and support of Industrial Automation systems with an emphasis on data collection, storage, and reporting.

# **Education**

## **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**

Western Illinois University | 2003 – 2007 | 4.0 Major, 3.8 Cumulative GPA, With Honors

Member of honor societies Phi Kappa Phi and Upsilon Pi Epsilon, received the "Outstanding Senior of 2007" award for the Computer Science department.

#### Skills

**Software Development:** OOP, UML, Design patterns, C#/.NET, Full-Stack web development, SQL, and Industrial-specific SCADA and MES packages. Unit testing, continuous integration and source control (SCM). **Systems Engineering:** Virtualization, Windows server administration, Linux/UNIX, hardware specification. **Project Management:** Requirements modeling and documentation, Design documentation, task and resource planning, Microsoft Project/Visio.